An American horror story.
The Apprentice is a history, drama film directed by Ali Abbasi.
A young Donald Trump, eager to make his name as a hungry scion of a wealthy family in 1970s New York, comes under
the spell of Roy Cohn, the cutthroat attorney who would help create the Donald Trump we know today.
Cohn sees in Trump the perfect protégé—someone with raw ambition, a hunger
for success, and a willingness to do whatever it takes to win.
Donald Trump, played by Sebastian Stan.
Roy Cohn, played by Jeremy Strong.
Fred Trump, played by Martin Donovan.
Ivana Trump, played by Maria Bakalova.
Mary Anne Trump, played by Catherine McNally.
Freddy Trump, played by Charlie Carrick.
The Apprentice is a 2024 independent biographical drama film
starring Sebastian Stan as President Donald Trump.
The plot examines Trump making a career as a real estate businessman in New York City in
the 1970s and 1980s, highlighting his relationship with attorney Roy Cohn.
Directed by Ali Abbasi and written by Gabriel Sherman, the film also stars Jeremy Strong as Cohn,
Martin Donovan as Trump's father Fred, and Maria Bakalova as Trump's first wife, Ivana.
An international co-production between Canada, Denmark, Ireland, and the United States, the biopic was
announced in May 2018, but languished until Abbasi, Stan, and Strong joined in 2023.
It premiered at the 77th Cannes Film Festival on May 20, 2024, and impressed the critics,
sparking an eight-minute standing ovation, and "feverish media attention".
However, the film struggled to find American distribution due to its subject
matter and an attempt by Trump's legal team to block its release.
Briarcliff eventually bought the rights, and
theatrically released it on October 11, 2024.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing $17
million worldwide on a $16 million budget.
The film received praise from critics for its acting, directing, and editing; Trump himself, meanwhile, described it as a
"defamatory, politically disgusting hatchet job" intended to harm his ultimately successful 2024 presidential campaign.
For their performances, Stan and Strong each received wide acclaim and recognition, including
respective nominations for Lead Actor and Supporting Actor at the 97th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of new york city, rape, corruption, aids, funeral.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.